PETER ANDRINGA

full stack web developer | entrepreneur | student

http://andrin.ga

□ peter@andrin.ga in /in/PeterAndringa

Profile

I'm a motivated and talented high school student who loves to build cool stuff, try new things, and turn my ideas into businesses. I may be young, but I have experience, skills, and a great work ethic. With experience working in a fast-paced startup development cycle, I'm the perfect fit for any startups, and I would love to hear from you if you have a open position!

Experience

DC Organizer, Pilot (Washington DC) — August 2013-Present

Pilot is an educational organization organizing and running events where high school students can learn how to conceive, build, and pitch their own ideas for web or mobile apps. I am the lead organizer of PilotDC (http://dc.gopilot.org), in charge of making sure the event runs smoothly.

Summer Associate, Social Tables (Washington DC) — July-August 2013

In Summer 2013 I worked at Social Tables (http://socialtables.com), a small startup offering web-based software for event professionals. In my time there I worked on their engineering team, using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Node.JS to rebuild their events dashboard, user page, and internal sales backend, among other projects.

CEO, Blue Spruce Games (Washington DC) — 2012-2013

In 2012-2013 I worked as the head of my (now closed) app development studio. The first app, Sharks Vs. Subs, made it to iOS, Android, and Nook, and received over 6,000 downloads before the studio was closed.

Education

Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology — Class of 2016

I currently attend TJHSST, a nationally-ranked magnet high school for students interested in science, math, and engineering. TJ offers a intense learning environment, which is both farreaching and very specific. I am currently taking the Computer Science track, and will be taking classes at the Human-Computer interactions lab next fall.

Skills

- Adept at Web Development with HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Skilled at server-side programming in Node.JS, Django, Java, and PHP
- Proficient in iOS App Development with Xcode and the Corona SDK
- Experienced with Linux Developer Operations

References

Available upon request